{"nodes":[{"content":"Voice and tone guidelines","pos":[2,27]},{"content":"Developers will be reading your documents to learn .NET core, and to use it in their regular work.","pos":[29,127]},{"content":"Your goal is to create useful documentation that helps the reader on their journey.","pos":[128,211],"source":"\nYour goal is to create useful documentation that helps the reader on their journey."},{"content":"Our guidelines help with that.","pos":[212,242],"source":" Our guidelines\nhelp with that."},{"content":"Our style guide contains four recommendations:","pos":[243,289]},{"content":"Use a Conversational Tone","pos":[293,318]},{"content":"Write in Second Person","pos":[351,373]},{"content":"Use Active Voice","pos":[400,416]},{"content":"Target a 5th Grade Reading Level","pos":[440,472]},{"content":"You will see examples of each of these as you read this style guide.","pos":[510,578]},{"content":"We've written this guide following our guidelines to provide examples for you to follow as you build documentation for .NET core.","pos":[579,708],"source":" We've written this guide\nfollowing our guidelines to provide examples for you to follow as you build documentation\nfor .NET core."},{"content":"We also provide contrasting samples so you can see what articles look like when you don't follow our guidelines.","pos":[709,821],"source":" We also provide contrasting samples so you can see what articles look like\nwhen you don't follow our guidelines."},{"content":"Details on each guideline","pos":[826,851]},{"content":"Use a Conversational Tone","pos":[857,882]},{"content":"Appropriate Style:","pos":[888,906]},{"content":"We want our documentation to have a conversational tone.","pos":[907,963]},{"content":"You should feel as though you are having a conversation with the author as you read any of our tutorials or explanations.","pos":[964,1085],"source":" You should feel as though you\nare having a conversation with the author as you read any of our tutorials or explanations."},{"content":"Your experience as a reader should be informal, conversational, and informative.","pos":[1086,1166],"source":"\nYour experience as a reader should be informal, conversational, and informative."},{"content":"You should feel as though you are listening to the author explain the concepts to you.","pos":[1167,1253],"source":" You should\nfeel as though you are listening to the author explain the concepts to you."},{"content":"Inappropriate Style:","pos":[1260,1280]},{"content":"One might see the contrast between a conversational style and the style one finds with more academic treatments of technical topics.","pos":[1281,1413],"source":"One might see the contrast between a conversational style and the style one finds with\nmore academic treatments of technical topics."},{"content":"Those resources are very useful, but the authors have written those articles in a very different style than our documentation.","pos":[1414,1540],"source":" Those resources are very useful, but the authors\nhave written those articles in a very different style than our documentation."},{"content":"When one reads an academic journal, one finds a very different tone and a very different style of writing.","pos":[1541,1647],"source":" When one reads\nan academic journal, one finds a very different tone and a very different style of writing."},{"content":"One feels that they are reading a dry account of a very dry topic.","pos":[1648,1714],"source":"\nOne feels that they are reading a dry account of a very dry topic."},{"content":"The first paragraph above follows our recommendation conversational style.","pos":[1718,1792]},{"content":"The second is a more academic style.","pos":[1793,1829],"source":" The second\nis a more academic style."},{"content":"You see the difference immediately.","pos":[1830,1865]},{"content":"Write in second person","pos":[1872,1894]},{"content":"Appropriate Style:","pos":[1900,1918]},{"content":"You should write your articles as though you are speaking directly to the reader.","pos":[1919,2000]},{"content":"You should use second person often (as I just have in these two sentences).","pos":[2001,2076],"source":" You\nshould use second person often (as I just have in these two sentences)."},{"content":"2nd person doesn't always mean using the word 'you'.","pos":[2077,2129],"source":" 2nd person doesn't\nalways mean using the word 'you'."},{"content":"Write directly to the reader.","pos":[2130,2159]},{"content":"Write imperative sentences.","pos":[2160,2187]},{"content":"Tell your reader what you want them to learn.","pos":[2188,2233],"source":"\nTell your reader what you want them to learn."},{"content":"Inappropriate Style:","pos":[2240,2260]},{"content":"An author could also choose to write in third person.","pos":[2262,2315]},{"content":"In that model, an author must find some pronoun or noun to use when referring to the reader.","pos":[2316,2408],"source":" In that model, an author must find some\npronoun or noun to use when referring to the reader."},{"content":"A reader might often find this third person style less engaging and less enjoyable to read.","pos":[2409,2500],"source":" A reader might often find this third\nperson style less engaging and less enjoyable to read."},{"content":"The first paragraph follows our recommended style.","pos":[2502,2552]},{"content":"The second uses third person.","pos":[2553,2582]},{"content":"Please write in second person.","pos":[2583,2613],"source":" Please write\nin second person."},{"content":"You probably found that much easier to read.","pos":[2614,2658]},{"content":"Use Active Voice","pos":[2664,2680]},{"content":"Write your articles in active voice.","pos":[2682,2718]},{"content":"Active voice means that the subject of the sentence performs the action (verb) of that sentence.","pos":[2719,2815],"source":" Active voice means that the subject of the sentence performs\nthe action (verb) of that sentence."},{"content":"It contrasts with passive voice, where the sentence is arranged such that the subject of the sentence is acted upon.","pos":[2816,2932],"source":" It contrasts with passive voice, where the sentence is arranged\nsuch that the subject of the sentence is acted upon."},{"content":"Contrast these two examples:","pos":[2933,2961]},{"content":"The compiler transformed source code into an executable.","pos":[2964,3020]},{"content":"The source code was transformed into an executable by the compiler.","pos":[3023,3090]},{"content":"The first sentence uses active voice.","pos":[3092,3129]},{"content":"The second sentence was written in passive voice.","pos":[3130,3179]},{"content":"(Those two sentences provide another example of each style).","pos":[3180,3240],"source":"\n(Those two sentences provide another example of each style)."},{"content":"We recommend active voice because it is more readable.","pos":[3242,3296]},{"content":"Passive voice can be more difficult to read.","pos":[3297,3341]},{"content":"Target a Fifth Grade Reading Level","pos":[3347,3381]},{"content":"We provide this final guideline because many of our readers are not native English speakers.","pos":[3383,3475]},{"content":"You are reaching an international audience with your articles.","pos":[3476,3538],"source":"\nYou are reaching an international audience with your articles."},{"content":"Please take into account that they may not have the English vocabulary you have.","pos":[3539,3619],"source":" Please take into account that\nthey may not have the English vocabulary you have."},{"content":"However, you are still writing for technical professionals.","pos":[3621,3680]},{"content":"You can assume that your readers have programming knowledge and the specific vocabulary for programming terms.","pos":[3681,3791],"source":" You can assume that your readers\nhave programming knowledge and the specific vocabulary for programming terms."},{"content":"Object Oriented Programming, Class, and Object, Function and Method will all be familiar terms.","pos":[3792,3887],"source":" Object Oriented\nProgramming, Class, and Object, Function and Method will all be familiar terms."},{"content":"However, not everyone reading your articles will have a formal computer science degree.","pos":[3888,3975],"source":" However, not everyone\nreading your articles will have a formal computer science degree."},{"content":"Terms like 'idempotent' probably need to be defined if you use it:","pos":[3976,4042],"source":" Terms like 'idempotent' probably\nneed to be defined if you use it:"},{"pos":[4045,4175],"content":"The Close() method is idempotent, meaning that you can call it multiple times and the effect is the same as if you called it once.","source":"The Close() method is idempotent, meaning that you can call it multiple times and the effect is\nthe same as if you called it once."}],"content":"# Voice and tone guidelines\n\nDevelopers will be reading your documents to learn .NET core, and to use it in their regular work.\nYour goal is to create useful documentation that helps the reader on their journey. Our guidelines\nhelp with that. Our style guide contains four recommendations:\n- [Use a Conversational Tone](#use-a-conversational-tone)\n- [Write in Second Person](#write-in-2nd-person)\n- [Use Active Voice](#use-active-voice)\n- [Target a 5th Grade Reading Level](#target-a-5th-grade-reading-level)\n\nYou will see examples of each of these as you read this style guide. We've written this guide\nfollowing our guidelines to provide examples for you to follow as you build documentation\nfor .NET core. We also provide contrasting samples so you can see what articles look like\nwhen you don't follow our guidelines.\n\n## Details on each guideline\n\n### Use a Conversational Tone\n#### Appropriate Style:\nWe want our documentation to have a conversational tone. You should feel as though you\nare having a conversation with the author as you read any of our tutorials or explanations.\nYour experience as a reader should be informal, conversational, and informative. You should\nfeel as though you are listening to the author explain the concepts to you.\n\n#### Inappropriate Style:\nOne might see the contrast between a conversational style and the style one finds with\nmore academic treatments of technical topics. Those resources are very useful, but the authors\nhave written those articles in a very different style than our documentation. When one reads\nan academic journal, one finds a very different tone and a very different style of writing.\nOne feels that they are reading a dry account of a very dry topic.  \n\nThe first paragraph above follows our recommendation conversational style. The second\nis a more academic style. You see the difference immediately. \n\n### Write in second person\n#### Appropriate Style:\nYou should write your articles as though you are speaking directly to the reader. You\nshould use second person often (as I just have in these two sentences). 2nd person doesn't\nalways mean using the word 'you'. Write directly to the reader. Write imperative sentences.\nTell your reader what you want them to learn.\n\n#### Inappropriate Style: \nAn author could also choose to write in third person. In that model, an author must find some\npronoun or noun to use when referring to the reader. A reader might often find this third\nperson style less engaging and less enjoyable to read.\n\nThe first paragraph follows our recommended style. The second uses third person. Please write\nin second person. You probably found that much easier to read.\n\n### Use Active Voice\n\nWrite your articles in active voice. Active voice means that the subject of the sentence performs\nthe action (verb) of that sentence. It contrasts with passive voice, where the sentence is arranged\nsuch that the subject of the sentence is acted upon. Contrast these two examples:\n\n>The compiler transformed source code into an executable.\n\n>The source code was transformed into an executable by the compiler.\n\nThe first sentence uses active voice. The second sentence was written in passive voice.\n(Those two sentences provide another example of each style).\n\nWe recommend active voice because it is more readable. Passive voice can be more difficult to read.\n\n### Target a Fifth Grade Reading Level\n\nWe provide this final guideline because many of our readers are not native English speakers.\nYou are reaching an international audience with your articles. Please take into account that\nthey may not have the English vocabulary you have.\n\nHowever, you are still writing for technical professionals. You can assume that your readers\nhave programming knowledge and the specific vocabulary for programming terms. Object Oriented\nProgramming, Class, and Object, Function and Method will all be familiar terms. However, not everyone\nreading your articles will have a formal computer science degree. Terms like 'idempotent' probably\nneed to be defined if you use it:\n\n>The Close() method is idempotent, meaning that you can call it multiple times and the effect is\nthe same as if you called it once."}