{"nodes":[{"pos":[12,51],"content":"Commands in a Makefile | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Commands in a Makefile | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"Commands in a Makefile","pos":[579,601]},{"content":"A description block or inference rule specifies a block of commands to run if the dependency is out-of-date.","pos":[602,710]},{"content":"NMAKE displays each command before running it, unless /S, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>.SILENT<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>!CMDSWITCHES<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or @ is used.","pos":[711,813],"source":" NMAKE displays each command before running it, unless /S, **.SILENT**, **!CMDSWITCHES**, or @ is used."},{"content":"NMAKE looks for a matching inference rule if a description block is not followed by a commands block.","pos":[814,915]},{"content":"A commands block contains one or more commands, each on its own line.","pos":[922,991]},{"content":"No blank line can appear between the dependency or rule and the commands block.","pos":[992,1071]},{"content":"However, a line containing only spaces or tabs can appear; this line is interpreted as a null command, and no error occurs.","pos":[1072,1195]},{"content":"Blank lines are permitted between command lines.","pos":[1196,1244]},{"content":"A command line begins with one or more spaces or tabs.","pos":[1251,1305]},{"content":"A backslash ( \\ ) followed by a newline character is interpreted as a space in the command; use a backslash at the end of a line to continue a command onto the next line.","pos":[1306,1476]},{"content":"NMAKE interprets the backslash literally if any other character, including a space or tab, follows the backslash.","pos":[1477,1590]},{"content":"A command preceded by a semicolon (;) can appear on a dependency line or inference rule, whether or not a commands block follows:","pos":[1597,1726]},{"content":"What do you want to know more about?","pos":[1804,1840]},{"content":"Command modifiers","pos":[1845,1862]},{"content":"Filename-parts syntax","pos":[1902,1923]},{"content":"Inline files in a makefile","pos":[1967,1993]},{"content":"See Also","pos":[2043,2051]},{"content":"NMAKE Reference","pos":[2056,2071]}],"content":"---\ntitle: \"Commands in a Makefile | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"11/04/2016\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"devlang-cpp\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"C++\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"commands, makefiles\"\nms.assetid: 8085517e-42f4-493b-b8f8-44311fc08c64\ncaps.latest.revision: 7\nauthor: \"corob-msft\"\nms.author: \"corob\"\nmanager: \"ghogen\"\ntranslation.priority.ht: \n  - \"cs-cz\"\n  - \"de-de\"\n  - \"es-es\"\n  - \"fr-fr\"\n  - \"it-it\"\n  - \"ja-jp\"\n  - \"ko-kr\"\n  - \"pl-pl\"\n  - \"pt-br\"\n  - \"ru-ru\"\n  - \"tr-tr\"\n  - \"zh-cn\"\n  - \"zh-tw\"\n---\n# Commands in a Makefile\nA description block or inference rule specifies a block of commands to run if the dependency is out-of-date. NMAKE displays each command before running it, unless /S, **.SILENT**, **!CMDSWITCHES**, or @ is used. NMAKE looks for a matching inference rule if a description block is not followed by a commands block.  \n  \n A commands block contains one or more commands, each on its own line. No blank line can appear between the dependency or rule and the commands block. However, a line containing only spaces or tabs can appear; this line is interpreted as a null command, and no error occurs. Blank lines are permitted between command lines.  \n  \n A command line begins with one or more spaces or tabs. A backslash ( \\ ) followed by a newline character is interpreted as a space in the command; use a backslash at the end of a line to continue a command onto the next line. NMAKE interprets the backslash literally if any other character, including a space or tab, follows the backslash.  \n  \n A command preceded by a semicolon (;) can appear on a dependency line or inference rule, whether or not a commands block follows:  \n  \n```  \nproject.obj : project.c project.h ; cl /c project.c  \n```  \n  \n## What do you want to know more about?  \n [Command modifiers](../build/command-modifiers.md)  \n  \n [Filename-parts syntax](../build/filename-parts-syntax.md)  \n  \n [Inline files in a makefile](../build/inline-files-in-a-makefile.md)  \n  \n## See Also  \n [NMAKE Reference](../build/nmake-reference.md)"}