{"nodes":[{"content":"Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation.","pos":[0,36]},{"content":"Distributed under the following terms:","pos":[38,76]},{"content":"Microsoft and any contributors to this project each grants you a license, under its respective copyrights, to the Microsoft Documentation under the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License<ept id=\"p1\">](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode)</ept>.","pos":[82,348],"source":"Microsoft and any contributors to this project each grants you a license, under its respective copyrights, to the Microsoft Documentation under the [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode)."},{"content":"In addition, with respect to any sample code contained in the documentation, Microsoft and any such contributors grants you an additional license, under its respective intellectual property rights, to use the code to develop or design your software for this product.","pos":[350,616]},{"content":"Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries.","pos":[623,843]},{"content":"This license does not grant you rights to use any names, logos, or trademarks.","pos":[844,922]},{"content":"For Microsoft’s general trademark guidelines, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653<ept id=\"p1\">](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653)</ept>.","pos":[923,1070],"source":" For Microsoft’s general trademark guidelines, go to [http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653)."},{"content":"Microsoft and any contributors reserves all others rights, whether under copyrights, patents, or trademarks, or by implication, estoppel or otherwise.","pos":[1077,1227]}],"content":"Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation.  Distributed under the following terms:\n \n1. Microsoft and any contributors to this project each grants you a license, under its respective copyrights, to the Microsoft Documentation under the [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode).  In addition, with respect to any sample code contained in the documentation, Microsoft and any such contributors grants you an additional license, under its respective intellectual property rights, to use the code to develop or design your software for this product.\n \n2.  Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries. This license does not grant you rights to use any names, logos, or trademarks. For Microsoft’s general trademark guidelines, go to [http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653).\n \n3.  Microsoft and any contributors reserves all others rights, whether under copyrights, patents, or trademarks, or by implication, estoppel or otherwise.\n\n"}