{"nodes":[{"pos":[12,41],"content":"ODBC Classes | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"ODBC Classes | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"ODBC Classes","pos":[639,651]},{"content":"These classes work with the other application framework classes to give easy access to a wide variety of databases for which Open Database Connectivity (ODBC) drivers are available.","pos":[652,833]},{"pos":[840,939],"content":"Programs that use ODBC databases will have at least a <ph id=\"ph1\">`CDatabase`</ph> object and a <ph id=\"ph2\">`CRecordset`</ph> object.","source":"Programs that use ODBC databases will have at least a `CDatabase` object and a `CRecordset` object."},{"content":"CDatabase","pos":[947,956]},{"content":"Encapsulates a connection to a data source, through which you can operate on the data source.","pos":[998,1091]},{"content":"CRecordset","pos":[1099,1109]},{"content":"Encapsulates a set of records selected from a data source.","pos":[1152,1210]},{"content":"Recordsets enable scrolling from record to record, updating records (adding, editing, and deleting records), qualifying the selection with a filter, sorting the selection, and parameterizing the selection with information obtained or calculated at run time.","pos":[1211,1468]},{"content":"CRecordView","pos":[1476,1487]},{"content":"Provides a form view directly connected to a recordset object.","pos":[1531,1593]},{"content":"The dialog data exchange (DDX) mechanism exchanges data between the recordset and the controls of the record view.","pos":[1594,1708]},{"content":"Like all form views, a record view is based on a dialog template resource.","pos":[1709,1783]},{"content":"Record views also support moving from record to record in the recordset, updating records, and closing the associated recordset when the record view closes.","pos":[1784,1940]},{"content":"CDBException","pos":[1948,1960]},{"content":"An exception resulting from failures in data access processing.","pos":[2005,2068]},{"content":"This class serves the same purpose as other exception classes in the exception-handling mechanism of the class library.","pos":[2069,2188]},{"content":"CFieldExchange","pos":[2196,2210]},{"content":"Supplies context information to support record field exchange (RFX), which exchanges data between the field data members and parameter data members of a recordset object and the corresponding table columns on the data source.","pos":[2257,2482]},{"content":"Analogous to class <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>CDataExchange<ept id=\"p1\">](../mfc/reference/cdataexchange-class.md)</ept>, which is used similarly for dialog data exchange (DDX).","pos":[2483,2615],"source":" Analogous to class [CDataExchange](../mfc/reference/cdataexchange-class.md), which is used similarly for dialog data exchange (DDX)."},{"content":"Related Classes","pos":[2624,2639]},{"content":"CLongBinary","pos":[2644,2655]},{"content":"Encapsulates a handle to storage for a binary large object (BLOB), such as a bitmap.","pos":[2699,2783]},{"content":"objects are used to manage large data objects stored in database tables.","pos":[2798,2870]},{"content":"CDBVariant","pos":[2878,2888]},{"content":"Allows you to store a value without worrying about the value's data type.","pos":[2931,3004]},{"content":"tracks the data type of the current value, which is stored in a union.","pos":[3018,3088]},{"content":"See Also","pos":[3097,3105]},{"content":"Class Overview","pos":[3110,3124]}],"content":"---\ntitle: \"ODBC Classes | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"11/04/2016\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"devlang-cpp\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\nf1_keywords: \n  - \"vc.classes.data\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"C++\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"database classes [C++], ODBC\"\n  - \"ODBC classes [C++]\"\nms.assetid: 6c40fca8-3033-4873-9abe-7f51725de0e0\ncaps.latest.revision: 9\nauthor: \"mikeblome\"\nms.author: \"mblome\"\nmanager: \"ghogen\"\ntranslation.priority.ht: \n  - \"cs-cz\"\n  - \"de-de\"\n  - \"es-es\"\n  - \"fr-fr\"\n  - \"it-it\"\n  - \"ja-jp\"\n  - \"ko-kr\"\n  - \"pl-pl\"\n  - \"pt-br\"\n  - \"ru-ru\"\n  - \"tr-tr\"\n  - \"zh-cn\"\n  - \"zh-tw\"\n---\n# ODBC Classes\nThese classes work with the other application framework classes to give easy access to a wide variety of databases for which Open Database Connectivity (ODBC) drivers are available.  \n  \n Programs that use ODBC databases will have at least a `CDatabase` object and a `CRecordset` object.  \n  \n [CDatabase](../mfc/reference/cdatabase-class.md)  \n Encapsulates a connection to a data source, through which you can operate on the data source.  \n  \n [CRecordset](../mfc/reference/crecordset-class.md)  \n Encapsulates a set of records selected from a data source. Recordsets enable scrolling from record to record, updating records (adding, editing, and deleting records), qualifying the selection with a filter, sorting the selection, and parameterizing the selection with information obtained or calculated at run time.  \n  \n [CRecordView](../mfc/reference/crecordview-class.md)  \n Provides a form view directly connected to a recordset object. The dialog data exchange (DDX) mechanism exchanges data between the recordset and the controls of the record view. Like all form views, a record view is based on a dialog template resource. Record views also support moving from record to record in the recordset, updating records, and closing the associated recordset when the record view closes.  \n  \n [CDBException](../mfc/reference/cdbexception-class.md)  \n An exception resulting from failures in data access processing. This class serves the same purpose as other exception classes in the exception-handling mechanism of the class library.  \n  \n [CFieldExchange](../mfc/reference/cfieldexchange-class.md)  \n Supplies context information to support record field exchange (RFX), which exchanges data between the field data members and parameter data members of a recordset object and the corresponding table columns on the data source. Analogous to class [CDataExchange](../mfc/reference/cdataexchange-class.md), which is used similarly for dialog data exchange (DDX).  \n  \n## Related Classes  \n [CLongBinary](../mfc/reference/clongbinary-class.md)  \n Encapsulates a handle to storage for a binary large object (BLOB), such as a bitmap. `CLongBinary` objects are used to manage large data objects stored in database tables.  \n  \n [CDBVariant](../mfc/reference/cdbvariant-class.md)  \n Allows you to store a value without worrying about the value's data type. `CDBVariant` tracks the data type of the current value, which is stored in a union.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [Class Overview](../mfc/class-library-overview.md)\n\n"}