{"nodes":[{"pos":[12,51],"content":"White-Space Characters | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"White-Space Characters | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"White-Space Characters","pos":[621,643]},{"content":"Space, tab, linefeed, carriage-return, formfeed, vertical-tab, and newline characters are called \"white-space characters\" because they serve the same purpose as the spaces between words and lines on a printed page — they make reading easier.","pos":[644,885]},{"content":"Tokens are delimited (bounded) by white-space characters and by other tokens, such as operators and punctuation.","pos":[886,998]},{"content":"When parsing code, the C compiler ignores white-space characters unless you use them as separators or as components of character constants or string literals.","pos":[999,1157]},{"content":"Use white-space characters to make a program more readable.","pos":[1158,1217]},{"content":"Note that the compiler also treats comments as white space.","pos":[1218,1277]},{"content":"See Also","pos":[1286,1294]},{"content":"C Tokens","pos":[1299,1307]}],"content":"---\ntitle: \"White-Space Characters | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"11/04/2016\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"devlang-cpp\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"C++\"\n  - \"C\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"white space, characters\"\n  - \"characters, white space\"\nms.assetid: 030ccbdc-2db3-4dd0-88c8-f5c2669ddebf\ncaps.latest.revision: 8\nauthor: \"mikeblome\"\nms.author: \"mblome\"\nmanager: \"ghogen\"\ntranslation.priority.ht: \n  - \"cs-cz\"\n  - \"de-de\"\n  - \"es-es\"\n  - \"fr-fr\"\n  - \"it-it\"\n  - \"ja-jp\"\n  - \"ko-kr\"\n  - \"pl-pl\"\n  - \"pt-br\"\n  - \"ru-ru\"\n  - \"tr-tr\"\n  - \"zh-cn\"\n  - \"zh-tw\"\n---\n# White-Space Characters\nSpace, tab, linefeed, carriage-return, formfeed, vertical-tab, and newline characters are called \"white-space characters\" because they serve the same purpose as the spaces between words and lines on a printed page — they make reading easier. Tokens are delimited (bounded) by white-space characters and by other tokens, such as operators and punctuation. When parsing code, the C compiler ignores white-space characters unless you use them as separators or as components of character constants or string literals. Use white-space characters to make a program more readable. Note that the compiler also treats comments as white space.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [C Tokens](../c-language/c-tokens.md)"}