{"nodes":[{"pos":[12,42],"content":"Pseudotargets | Microsoft Docs","needQuote":false,"needEscape":true,"nodes":[{"content":"Pseudotargets | Microsoft Docs","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"Pseudotargets","pos":[710,723]},{"content":"A pseudotarget is a label used in place of a filename in a dependency line.","pos":[724,799]},{"content":"It is interpreted as a file that does not exist, and so is out-of-date.","pos":[800,871]},{"content":"NMAKE assumes a pseudotarget's timestamp is the most recent of all its dependents.","pos":[872,954]},{"content":"If it has no dependents, the current time is assumed.","pos":[955,1008]},{"content":"If a pseudotarget is used as a target, its commands are always executed.","pos":[1009,1081]},{"content":"A pseudotarget used as a dependent must also appear as a target in another dependency.","pos":[1082,1168]},{"content":"However, that dependency does not need to have a commands block.","pos":[1169,1233]},{"content":"Pseudotarget names follow the filename syntax rules for targets.","pos":[1240,1304]},{"content":"However, if the name does not have an extension (that is, does not contain a period), it can exceed the 8-character limit for filenames and can be up to 256 characters long.","pos":[1305,1478]},{"content":"See Also","pos":[1487,1495]},{"content":"Targets","pos":[1500,1507]}],"content":"---\ntitle: \"Pseudotargets | Microsoft Docs\"\nms.custom: \"\"\nms.date: \"11/04/2016\"\nms.reviewer: \"\"\nms.suite: \"\"\nms.technology: \n  - \"devlang-cpp\"\nms.tgt_pltfrm: \"\"\nms.topic: \"article\"\ndev_langs: \n  - \"C++\"\nhelpviewer_keywords: \n  - \"makefiles, pseudotargets\"\n  - \"pseudotargets and NMAKE\"\n  - \"NMAKE program, pseudotargets\"\n  - \"timestamps, makefile pseudotargets\"\n  - \"NMAKE program, targets\"\nms.assetid: c8c479dc-0129-4186-8366-bc6251f2b494\ncaps.latest.revision: 7\nauthor: \"corob-msft\"\nms.author: \"corob\"\nmanager: \"ghogen\"\ntranslation.priority.ht: \n  - \"cs-cz\"\n  - \"de-de\"\n  - \"es-es\"\n  - \"fr-fr\"\n  - \"it-it\"\n  - \"ja-jp\"\n  - \"ko-kr\"\n  - \"pl-pl\"\n  - \"pt-br\"\n  - \"ru-ru\"\n  - \"tr-tr\"\n  - \"zh-cn\"\n  - \"zh-tw\"\n---\n# Pseudotargets\nA pseudotarget is a label used in place of a filename in a dependency line. It is interpreted as a file that does not exist, and so is out-of-date. NMAKE assumes a pseudotarget's timestamp is the most recent of all its dependents. If it has no dependents, the current time is assumed. If a pseudotarget is used as a target, its commands are always executed. A pseudotarget used as a dependent must also appear as a target in another dependency. However, that dependency does not need to have a commands block.  \n  \n Pseudotarget names follow the filename syntax rules for targets. However, if the name does not have an extension (that is, does not contain a period), it can exceed the 8-character limit for filenames and can be up to 256 characters long.  \n  \n## See Also  \n [Targets](../build/targets.md)"}